<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="easy3_count" translatable="false">0</string>

    <string name="easy3_p1_1">Preparatory stage</string>
    <string name="easy3_p2_1">Cube\'s design</string>

    <string name="easy3_1_1"><b>Center pieces</b> (6 pcs.) Centers never change their position in relation to each other and always stay in the same place. Therefore, the following pattern can be observed: the center piece colors are always opposite each other - white is opposite yellow, blue is opposite green, and orange is opposite red. Hence, the color of the center determines the color of the face (blue center means that the face has to be blue, etc.).</string>
    <string name="easy3_1_2"><b>Edge pieces</b> (12 pcs.) The edges have two stickers of different colors and form a kind of cross when they are in the right place. These two stickers cannot be separated.</string>
    <string name="easy3_1_3"><b>Corner pieces</b> (8 pcs.) The corner pieces have 3 stickers of different colors. They cannot be split as well.</string>

    <string name="easy3_p2_2">Sides</string>

    <string name="easy3_2_1"><b>Sides of the Rubik\'s Cube</b> are 9 elements that can be rotated simultaneously.\n\nAlgorithms will help us to solve the Cube. A letter followed by an apostrophe, or \"prime\" as it is called by the speedcubers, indicates a counterclockwise turn. To avoid confusion, imagine that you are looking at the rotating side.\n\nFor example, <b>R</b> means that you should turn the right side clockwise, while <b>R\'</b> denotes a counterclockwise rotation.</string>

    <string name="easy3_2_r">Right side\nMove <b>R</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_nr">Right side\nMove <b>R\'</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_l">Left side\nMove <b>L</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_nl">Left side\nMove <b>L\'</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_u">Move <b>U</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_nu">Move <b>U\'</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_d">Move <b>D</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_nd">Move <b>D\'</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_f">Move <b>F</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_nf">Move <b>F\'</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_b">Move <b>B</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_2_nb">Move <b>B\'</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_p1_2">Stage 1. The proper cross</string>
    <string name="easy3_p2_3">Flower</string>

    <string name="easy3_3_1">We will divide solving the proper cross into two steps: the first one is to make a flower pattern, which we will then turn into a cross in the second stage.</string>
    <string name="easy3_3_2">Our goal is to create a flower with a yellow center and white petals (Pic. 1). Hold the cube so that the yellow center piece is on top of the cube.\n\nWhen the flower is ready, we will replace its yellow center with the white one to transform it into a cross. (Pic. 2)</string>
    <string name="easy3_3_3"><b>Flower</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_3_4"><b>Cross</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_sv_1">To make a flower, we need to find all 4 white edge pieces and surround the yellow center with them. It is an easy thing to. You can do it intuitively and move to the next step.</string>
    <string name="easy3_res"><b>Result</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_sv_2">1. If there are white pieces on the middle layer, simply move them up using the R algorithm. Repeat this step with all the edge pieces of the middle layer.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sv_2_1">1. Do <b>R</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_sv_3">2. If there is an edge piece on the middle layer, but another piece does not let you place it in the correct position, move this part using the U move and then use the R move to put the edge piece in the right spot.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sv_3_1">2. Do <b>U R</b></string>


    <string name="easy3_sv_4_h">We are done with the middle layer. Let\'s proceed with the bottom one.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sv_4">3. If the white sticker on piece that we need faces down, simply move it up using two R moves, which are referred to as R2 in the formulas.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sv_4_1">3. Do <b>R2</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_sv_5">4. If the piece that you want to relocate on the top or the bottom layer and its white sticker faces you (Pic. 4 or 5), then first you should move it to the middle layer using the F move, and then you can put it in the correct position (if there is another piece there, do U or U\' to remove it).</string>
    <string name="easy3_sv_5_1">4. <b>F U L\'</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_sv_5_2">5. <b>F U\' R</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_sv_endH">Congratulations!</string>
    <string name="easy3_sv_end">If you have managed to solve the flower pattern, you will not find the following steps difficult. The flower is the hardest stage to understand for beginners.</string>

    <string name="easy3_p2_4">Cross</string>
    <string name="easy3_cross_1">It is very simple, and it takes just a few movements to turn the flower into the proper cross.</string>
    <string name="easy3_cross_2_1">Look at the flower and pay attention to the color of the edges. Choose any of them, match it to the center piece of the same color and move it down using the F2 algorithm. Repeat this step with all the edge pieces.</string>
    <string name="easy3_cross_2_3"><b>F2</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_cross_3_1">When you are done with the edges, turn the entire cube over and you will see that the white cross is ready.</string>
    <string name="easy3_cross_3_2">Please, note that the colors of the edges in the cross should match those of the centers. If suddenly you got the wrong cross, please try once again!</string>
    <string name="easy3_cross_3_3"><b>Proper cross</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_cross_3_4"><b>Wrong crosss</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_fl_h1">Stage 2. The first layer</string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_h2_1">Corners</string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_1_1"><b>Without corners</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_1_2"><b>With corners</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_1_3">Our next step is to solve the corners (the 3-colored pieces). As a result, our first layer should be completed.</string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_1_4">But first, let\'s learn a very simple but effective formula called PIF-PAF. It includes a sequence of 4 moves: <b>R U R\' U\'</b>, simply put, <b>up-left-down-right</b>.</string>

    <string name="easy3_fl_2_1"><b>Pic. 1</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_2_2"><b>Pic. 2</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_2_3">Move the cross down (Pic. 1). Find a corner with the white color on the top layer (Pic. 2).</string>


    <string name="easy3_fl_3_1"><b>R U R\' U\'</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_3_2">If, for example, the corner is colored green and red, put it between the green and red centers and follow the PIF-PAF algorithm.</string>

    <string name="easy3_fl_4_1"><b>(R U R\' U\')x3</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_4_2">Depending on the situation, you should repeat the PIF–PAF algorithm 1–5 times. If, for example, the white sticker of the corner faces up, you should do it 3 times.</string>

    <string name="easy3_fl_5_1"><b>(R U R\' U\')x2</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_5_2">If you notice that the corner is in the correct position, but you still need to turn it, follow the PIF-PAF algorithm. Spin until the corner piece is in the right place.</string>

    <string name="easy3_fl_6_1"><b>R U R\' U\'</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_fl_6_2">If you were unlucky and ran out of the corners with the white stickers on the top layer, you should replace the misplaced piece using the PIF-PAF once, and continue to arrange the corner pieces as you did before.</string>
    <string name="easy_fl_h2_2">Congratulations, you\'ve finished the first layer!</string>

    <string name="easy3_sl_h1">Stage 3. The middle layer</string>

    <string name="easy3_sl_1_1">To complete the second layer, you should move one of the edge pieces at a time from the top layer to the middle one. To do so, you should learn to follow the PIF-PAF algorithm using your left hand: <b>L\' U\' L U</b> In other words, your left hand goes <b>up-right-down-left</b>.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_1_2"><b>One layer</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_1_3"><b>Two layers</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_sl_h2_2">The edge piece goes to the right.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_2_1">You should pay particular attention to the colors. For example, let\'s take the edge piece colored green and red. You should move it to ensure that its red sticker is located next to the red center piece and hold the cube so that the red cubies face you (Pic. 1).</string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_2_2">Do <b>U  R U R\' U\' y L\' U\' L U</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_2_3">y means rotating the cube on the Y axis to the right. In this case, the green center piece should be in front of you. In other words, the formula implies: the right PIF-PAF, rotating the cube on the Y axis to the right, and the left PIF-PAF.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_2_4"><b>Pic. 1</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_sl_h2_3">The edge piece goes to the left</string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_3_1">If you put the green and red edge piece next to the green center (Pic. 2), you can notice that this time the edge will go to the left.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_3_2">So you should do <b>U\' L\' U\' L U y\' R U R\' U\'</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_3_3"><b>y\'</b> means rotating the cube on the Y axis to the left. In this case, the red center piece will be in front of you. In other words, this formula implies: left PIF-PAF, rotating the cube on the Y axis to the left, right PIF-PAF.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_3_4"><b>Pic. 2</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_sl_h2_4">There are no edge pieces anymore</string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_4_1">If you were unlucky and ran out of the edges on the top layer, and, as a result, failed to complete the second layer – it is not a problem! Put the wrongly assembled edge on the right (Pic. 3) and do <b>R U R\' U\' y L\' U\' L U</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_4_2">In other words, it means: the right PIF-PAF, rotating the cube on the Y axis to the right (the green center piece should be in front of you), the left PIF-PAF, and after that you can arrange the edge pieces the way you did it before.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_4_3">Congratulations, after you have solved the edge pieces in the second layer, the cube is 60 percent ready. Less than half of the beginners can reach this stage, so if you managed to do it, you are doing a great job and your Rubik\'s Cube will be solved really soon.</string>
    <string name="easy3_sl_4_4"><b>Pic. 3</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_ll_h1">Stage 4. Edges of the last layer</string>

    <string name="easy3_yc_h2_1">Yellow cross</string>

    <string name="easy3_yc_1_1">We have nearly solved the cube. You are almost there. At this stage, you should flip the cube once again so that the yellow pieces are on the top.</string>
    <string name="easy3_yc_1_2">Your yellow cross should undergo the following transformations:\na single dot → half a cross (nine o\'clock) → a line → a cross</string>
    <string name="easy3_yc_1_3">Maybe, the cross has already been formed on your cube as a result of the previous steps. But you can\'t always be that lucky. Sometimes you may get just one lonely dot, which you will have to gradually turn into the cross.</string>
    <string name="easy3_yc_1_4"><b>Dot</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_yc_1_5"><b>Half cross (nine o\'clock)</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_yc_2_1">Regardless of the figure that you got, do <b>F R U R\' U\' F\'</b>. Simply put, <b>F (PIF-PAF) F\'</b>.</string>
    <string name="easy3_yc_2_2">Please, note that if you got a half cross, you should hold the cube so that it resembles the clock with the hour hand pointing to the clock number nine and the minute one – to twelve. If you got the line, put it in a horizontal position before starting the algorithm.</string>
    <string name="easy3_yc_2_3">If you entered this stage with a dot, it will turn into a half cross; if you already have a half cross, it will turn into a line, and if you have a line, it will turn into a cross.</string>
    <string name="easy3_yc_2_4"><b>Attention!</b>\nIf 1 or 3 elements are placed face up at the same time and you cannot see any of the figures that we\'ve described before, your cube must have been taken apart and assembled incorrectly (it could\'ve happened accidentally or perhaps someone wanted to play a little joke on you). In this case, you will not manage to solve the cube following the formulas. We strongly recommend you to reassemble the cube mechanically in accordance with the colors.</string>
    <string name="easy3_yc_2_5"><b>Line</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_yc_2_6"><b>Cross</b></string>


    <string name="easy3_tyc_h2_1">The proper yellow cross</string>

    <string name="easy3_tyc_1_1">The cross that you will finally get may turn out to be incorrect (Pic. 1). You should make sure that all the colors of the edge pieces constituting the cross (3 layers) match the center pieces (Pic. 2).</string>
    <string name="easy3_tyc_1_2">Attention, there can be only three scenarios:\n1. The neighboring edges coincide\n2. The opposite edges coincide\n3. You are lucky, as you\'ve got the proper cross straightaway or you just need to fix the top layer.</string>
    <string name="easy3_tyc_1_3"><b>Pic. 1</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_tyc_1_4"><b>Pic. 2</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_tyc_2_1">1. The neighboring edges coincide\nIf these two pieces are adjacent, put them on the right and back, follow the <b>R U R\' U R U2 R\' U</b>  algorithm. You should get the proper cross (the color of its edges should match that of the centers).</string>
    <string name="easy3_tyc_2_2"><b>The neighboring edges</b></string>

    <string name="easy3_tyc_3_1">2. The opposite edges coincide\nIf these two opposite pieces coincide, put them in front and behind, do <b>R U R\' U R U2 R\'</b>. This should lead you to the previous situation (when the neighboring edges coincide).</string>
    <string name="easy3_tyc_3_2"><b>The opposite edges</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_tyc_3_3"><b>The neighboring edges</b></string>


    <string name="easy3_pcll_h1">Stage 5. Solving corners of the third layer</string>
    <string name="easy3_pcll_text1">First, check how many corners are in the correct positions: all of them, one or not a single one. If all the corners are in the right place, skip this step and move on to the next one. \n\nThe yellow stickers of the corner pieces can face any direction. The main thing is to make sure that the corner colored orange and green is located between the orange and the green center pieces, the corner colored green and red is between the green and the red centers, etc.</string>
    <string name="easy3_pcll_text2">If none of the corner pieces is placed correctly, follow this algorithm:\n<b>R U\' L\' U R\' U\' L U</b>\n\nAfter this, you will get one properly located corner. Put it on the left and on the top (right where your left thumb is) and repeat the algorithm. If it didn\'t work, put it in the bottom left position and repeat one again.\n\n<b>Attention!</b>\nIf only 2 or 3 pieces are in their due places, your cube must have been taken apart and assembled incorrectly. In this case, you will not manage to solve the cube following the formulas. Reassemble the cube mechanically in accordance with the colors.\n\nWhen all the corner pieces are in correct positions, all you have to do is just to turn them to finish solving the cube.</string>
    <string name="easy3_pcll_1"><b>All the corners are placed incorrectly </b></string>
    <string name="easy3_pcll_2"><b>One corner is in the right place</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_pcll">Pic. 1: All the corners are placed incorrectly\nPic. 2: One corner is in the right place</string>

    <string name="easy3_ocll_h1">Final stage. Corners orientation.</string>
    <string name="easy3_ocll_text1">We are going to turn the corners using the PIF-PAF moves (<b>R U R\' U\'</b>). It is a simple formula that you already know very well!</string>
    <string name="easy3_ocll_text2">Once again, check that all the corners are in the right places (Pic. 1). Hold the cube so that the corners that have to be oriented are on the bottom (Pic. 2).</string>
    <string name="easy3_ocll_text3">Start with any unfinished corner and repeat PIF-PAFs until the corner is ready. (Pic. 3)\nThen twist the bottom layer, and proceed to the next corner (Pic. 4).</string>
    <string name="easy3_ocll_text4">Continue doing PIF-PAFS until the 2nd corner is completed (Pic. 5) and so on.\n\n<b>ATTENTION!</b> If the corner is already solved, you still need to finish the sequence of the PIF-PAF moves, and only then proceed to the next pieces.\nWhen you are done with all of the corners, the cube will be solved. Do not forget to complete the last move.\n\n<b>Warning</b>\nIt\'s the step where you are most likely to make a mistake. Therefore, be careful, otherwise you will have to start solving the cube from the very beginning.</string>
    <string name="easy3_ocll_1_1"><b>Pic. 1</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_ocll_1_2"><b>Pic. 2</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_ocll_2_1"><b>Pic. 3</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_ocll_2_2"><b>Pic. 4</b></string>
    <string name="easy3_ocll_3_1"><b>Pic. 5</b></string>

    <string name="easy_3_out_h1">Congratulations!</string>
    <string name="easy_3_out_text">Good job! You have managed to solve your first Rubik\'s Cube.\nShare it with your friends.</string>
</resources>